Rahul Agrawal

Software Engineer 2

rahulagrawal0310@gmail.com

+91-9560223458

Bengaluru, India

linkedin.com/in/rahul-agrawal-686772a5

Highly skilled IT professional with 5.2 years of experience in designing and implementing scalable and resilient software solutions while working in a fast-paced agile environment. Have worked across multiple business domains including banking, e-commerce, automotive and location services.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages &

Scala, Akka, Play, Java, Spring Boot, Python

Programming Paradigms

Functional, Reactive, Object-Oriented

Frameworks

Git, AWS(S3, Kinesis), Jenkins, Gitlab, Kafka,

Spark, Docker, Splunk, Grafana, Kibana,

DataDog, SwaggerUI

Databases

Postgres, DynamoDB, Oracle, SQL

Server, Vertica

APIs

Tools

RESTful, SOAP

Methodologies

Scrum, Agile

SOFT SKILLS

Excellent Written/Oral Communication

Attention To Detail

Team Work

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 2

HERE Technologies

04/2022 - Present Remote, India

HERE is a PaaS for building, deploying and scaling location solutions

- Projects/Tasks
- Took ownership of the subscription management micro-service(Entitlement Center) that manages access to map services for millions of automotive client users. My responsibilities include - developing new APIs, optimising workflows, bug-fixing and maintenance work. Primary tech stack comprises of Scala, Akka, Play, Gitlab, K8, DynamoDB and AWS.
- Actively involved in developing a pipeline to ingest, process and publish night time construction events as part of broader map content generation. Pipeline was built on Scala, Java, Akka, Spark, AWS etc.
- Mentoring new recruits in the team and educating them on company culture and technical aspects of the project.

Software Consultant

Knoldus Inc. | Part of Nashtech

04/2020 - 04/2022 Noida, India

A startup with a product oriented mindset that focusses in functional programming technologies like Scala, Akka, Java 8+ and Big Data technologies like Spark, Kafka, Snowflake etc.

Projects/Tasks

- Cross-border E-Commerce Designed and developed back-end features (orders, experiences, logistics & billing) for a global e-commerce company that allows merchants to sell products globally and provides local shopping experiences to customers. The platform was based on a micro-service architecture with an API first approach. Services were built on Scala, Play, Akka with AWS Kinesis for event streaming and a Postgres database behind each service.
- Contributed to building a streaming data pipeline that serves sensor data to a data analytics platform for a multinational information technology company. Tech stack - Scala, Akka, Kafka, Spark and Vertica with Grafana/Prometheus for monitoring.
- Designed and implemented a data-driven test automation framework using Java8, RestAssured and TestNg for a global risk management company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Newgen Software Technologies Ltd.

07/2018 - 03/2020

Deals in BPM, ECM & CCM products across countries

- Proiects/Tasks
- Designed and implemented APIs that serve interactive dashboards used to automate asset monitoring and reporting processes for a Fortune 500 bank. Dashboards were built using Java, Spring MVC, Servlets and Oracle DB alongwith Angular for UI.
- Trade Finance Contributed to the development of a trade finance platform for a leading bank using a mix of Java, Javascript, Oracle and company-owned products.
- Worked extensively with overseas client teams to achieve mutual success by delivering high quality software systems.

EDUCATION

B.Tech, Computer Science & Engineering

AKGEC, Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University

08/2014 - 07/2018 73.6%

Senior Year(12th Standard)

St. Joseph's College, Allahabad

04/2012 - 04/2013

Secondary Grade (10th Standard)

St. Joseph's College, Allahabad

04/2010 - 04/2011 87.7%

RECOGNITION

Top Performer (Leadership Forum) - Award received for outstanding contributions within 6 months of joining. (HERE Technologies)

Pat On The Back - Received recognition from a global ecommerce client for individually completing a tricky feature to enable multi-account connection of their ecommerce platform with Google Merchant Center for generating product feeds for advertisement. (Knoldus Inc.)

Chipping In - Recognition for constantly helping teammates with their work. (Knoldus Inc.)

SIDE-PROJECTS

Automatic Data Migration - A streaming data pipeline that streams records from MySQL to PostgreSQL database taking only the source and destination database URLs as inputs. Pipeline is built on Scala, Slick and Akka Streams.

Online Banking System - A J2EE based web app that lets users deposit, withdraw, send and receive money along with getting their account statements.

INTERESTS

Technology Investing Sports

LANGUAGES

English Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native Language/Full Proficiency

Noida, India

83 2%